Guide to the Research Institute for the Study of Man (RISM) Vertical Files RISM.VF.1
New York University Archives
- Barbados
  - Barbados: History (Box 2)
    - Father Antoine Biet's Visit to Barbados in 1654, 1967; RISM 12384; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 56-76. (Box 2)
      History.; Barbados.
    - "Memoirs of an Old Army Officer": Richard A. Wyvill's Visits to Barbados in 1796 and 1806-7, 1975; RISM 25833; Wyvill, Richard Augustus; p. 21-30. (Box 2)
    - A Seventeenth Century Commentary on Labor and Military Problems in Barbados, 1973; RISM 25840; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 117-121. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Housing (Box 2)
    - Barbados Housing Authority: Tenth Annual Report, 1965-1966, 1967; RISM 20067; Barbados. Housing Authority; 57 pages (Box 2)
      Housing.; Barbados.
    - Report on Preliminary Housing Survey of Two Blocks of Chapman's Lane Tenantry, Bridgetown; and Comments of the Report by the Town Planning Adviser and the Housing Board, 1944; RISM 20068; Desyllas, L. M.; 8 pages (Box 2)
    - Report on a Housing Survey of Eight Slum Tenantries in Bridgetown, June 1944-April 1945, RISM 20069; Barbados. Housing Board Office; 47 pages (Box 2)
    - An Act to Provide for Chattel Houses Built from Labour Welfare Funds and now vested in the Executive Committee, to be vested in the Housing Authority, 1958; 6 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Income (Box 2)
    - Annual Report of the Commissioner of Inland Revenue, 1955-1959; RISM 16500; Barbados. Department of Inland Revenue; 4 items; no content (Box 2)
      Income.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Indentured Servants (Box 2)
    - A German Indentured Servant in Barbados in 1652: The Account of Heinrich Von Uchteritz, 1970; RISM 20070; Von Uchteritz, Heinrich; p. 91-100. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Indentured servants.
    - From Land to Sea: Runaway Slaves and White Indentured Servants in Seventeenth Century Barbados, 1984; RISM 20198; Beckles, Hilary, 1955-; 26 pages (Box 2)
    - The "Redlegs" of Barbados; Book Review, 1979; RISM 24177; Mintz, Sidney W. (Sidney Wilfred), 1922-2015; p. 414-416. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Indians of the Caribbean (Box 2)
    - Aspects of Amerindian Ethnography in 17th Century Barbados, 1970; RISM 12339; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 50-72 (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Indians of the West Indies.
    - Amerindians and Their Contributions to Barbadian Life in the Seventeenth Century, 1977; RISM 25826; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 189-210 (Box 2)
    - The Amerindian Slave Population of Barbados in the Seventeenth and Early Eighteenth Centuries, 1969; RISM 12341; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 38-64. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Irrigation (Box 2)
    - The Irrigation Board; An Interim Report, 1960 to 1963, RISM 20071; Hudson, J. C. (John Corrie), 1796-1879; 42 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Irrigation.
  - Barbados: Jews (Box 2)
    - Items from the Old Minute Book of the Sephardic Congregation of Hamburg, Relating to the Jews of Barbados, 1931; RISM 20072; p.114-116 (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Jews.
  - Barbados: Land Tenure (Box 2)
    - Land Tenure and Transmission in Rural Barbados, 1960; RISM 20073; Greenfield, Sidney M.; 9 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Land tenure.
  - Barbados: Land Use (Box 2)
    - Stocks, Bonds, and Peasant Canes in Barbados: Some Notes on the Use of Land in an 0verdeveloped Economy, 1964; RISM 20074; Greenfield, Sidney M.; p. 619-650. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Land use.
  - Barbados: Libraries (Box 2)
    - Barbados Public Library, West Indian Collection: Additions 1976-1977, 18 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Libraries
  - Barbados: Local Government (Box 2)
    - An Act to Provide for the Establishment of a Local Government Service Commission and to Make Provision in Respect of Matters Relating to the Terms and Conditions of Service of Persons Employed in Local Government Service, 1959; RISM 23082; 15 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Local government.
    - An Act to Amend the Local Government Act, 1958, 1959; RISM 23083; 9 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Maroons (Box 2)
    - Runaway Slaves in Nineteenth-Century Barbados, 1984; RISM 20075; Heuman, Gad J.; 25 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Maroons.
    - Escaping Slavery in a Caribbean Plantation Society: Marronage in Barbados, 1650s-1830s, 1997; RISM 24363; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 183-225. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Medical Care (Box 2)
    - Health Services in Barbados for the Year, 1967-1971; RISM 20076; Barbados. Ministry of Health and Community Development; 3 items; 1967, 1967, 1971; no content (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Medical care.
  - Barbados: Mental Illness (Box 2)
    - The Barbadian Mental Patient As Social Observer, 1973; RISM 20300; Fisher, Lawrence Edgar; 6 pages (Box 2)
      Mental illness.; Barbados.
    - Court Remands to the Barbados Mental Hospital, 1971; RISM 23084; Fisher, Lawrence Edgar; 4 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Military Assistance, American (Box 2)
    - Peacekeeping; Agreement Between the United States of America and Barbados, Effected by Exchange of Notes, 1983-1984; RISM 20080; United States. Department of State; 4 pages (Box 2)
      Military assistance American.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Military Education (Box 2)
    - International Military Education and Training (IMET); Agreement Between the United States of America and Barbados, Effected by Exchange of Notes, 1980; RISM 20081; United States. Department of State; 5 pages (Box 2)
      Military education.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Natural Resources (Box 2)
    - Persistence and Change in the Vegetation of Oceanic Islands: An Example from Barbados, West Indies, 1970; RISM 20082; Watts, David; p. 91-109. (Box 2)
      Natural resources.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Petroleum Industry and Trade (Box 2)
    - General Crude Pressing Barbados Hunt, 1967; RISM 23035; p. 64-65. (Box 2)
      Petroleum industry and trade.; Barbados.
    - An Act to Amend the Natural Gas Corporation Act, 1950, 1958; 15 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Plantations (Box 2)
    - Some Aspects of Work Organization on Sugar Plantations in Barbados, 1965; RISM 12313; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 16-36 (Box 2)
      Plantations.; Barbados.
    - Temporomandibular Joint Size Decrease in American Blacks: Evidence from Barbados, 1980; RISM 20083; Corruccini, Robert S.; p. 1528. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Plantations.
    - The Plantation Great Houses of Barbados, undated; RISM 20084; Fraser, Henry S. (Henry Salmon), 1900-2001; p. 15-16. (Box 2)
    - The Problem of Slave Labor Supply at the Codrington Plantations, 1952; RISM 20085; Bennett, J. Harry; p. 115-141. (Box 2)
    - Tooth Mutilation in the Caribbean: Evidence from a Slave Burial Population in Barbados, 1982; RISM 20086; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 297-313. (Box 2)
    - Patterning of Skeletal Lead Content in Barbados Slaves, 1987; RISM 20087; Corruccini, Robert S.; p. 233-239. (Box 2)
    - Letters on the Labouring Population of Barbados, 1858, 1990; RISM 20089; Pinder, Edward; 48 pages (Box 2)
    - Implications of Tooth Root Hypercementosis in a Barbados Slave Skeletal Collection, 1987; RISM 20088; Corruccini, Robert S.; p.179-184. (Box 7)
  - Barbados: Poetry (Box 2)
    - "29 Poems": Poems, 1948-1958, ca. 1959; RISM 23085; Carter, Lionel D.; 30 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Poetry.
  - Barbados: Political Parties (Box 2)
    - Labour Marches On: A Record of Achievements and a Statement of the Future Policy of the Barbados Labour Party, 1951; RISM 11005; Barbados Labour Party; 12.0 (Box 2)
      Political parties.; Barbados.
    - Mass Political Party Institutionalisation in Barbados: An Analysis of the Issues and Dynamics of the Post-Independence Period, 1981; RISM 20090; Will, W. Marvin; p. 134-156. (Box 2)
    - Operation Takeover: Manifesto of the Democratic Labour Party; Barbados General Election, 1961, RISM 20091; Democratic Labour Party (Barbados); 16 pages (Box 2)
    - Manifesto of the Barbados Labour Party: General Elections, 1971, Barbados Labour Party; 24 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Politics and Government (Box 2)
    - Barbados: The Politics of Cricket and Cane, 1969; RISM 16949; McDonald, Frank; 23 pages (Box 2)
      Politics and government.; Barbados.
    - Administrative Change and Development in Barbados, undated; RISM 16950; Khan, Jamal; p. 149-158. (Box 2)
    - The Preservation of Democracy in Barbados, 1967; RISM 16951; 36 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Population (Box 2)
    - Report of the Joint Committee to Examine the Question of Over-Population in Barbados, 1953; RISM 20058; Barbados. Legislature. Joint Committee to Examine the Question of Over-Population in Barbados and to make Recommendations for Dealing with this Problem; 12 pages (Box 2)
      Population.; Barbados.
    - The Population of Barbados, 1957; RISM 20059; Lowenthal, David; p. 445-501. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Population.
    - Report on Vital Statistics and Registrations for the Year, 1953-1959; RISM 23215; Barbados. Registration Office; 3 items; 1953, 1957, 1959.; no content (Box 2)
    - Census Bulletins of the 1960 Population Census of Barbados, RISM 23332; Trinidad and Tobago. Population Census Division; 6 items; unpaged; duplicates; no content (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Proverbs (Box 2)
    - Bajan Proverbs, 1985 (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Proverbs.
  - Barbados: Pottery (Box 2)
    - Pottery Making in Rural Barbados, 1983; RISM 4116; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 314-334. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Pottery.
    - A Historical Sketch of Pottery Manufacturing in Barbados, 1963; RISM 12306; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 1-24. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Power Resources (Box 2)
    - Brace Research Institute: Energy as a Major Factor in Man's Development, 1964; RISM 20093; Ward, G. T. (Gerald Templeton); 22 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Power resources.
  - Barbados: Printing (Box 2)
    - Some Notes on Early Printing Presses and Newspapers in Barbados, 1958; RISM 20094; Shilstone, E. M., 1889-1969; p. 19-33. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Printing.
  - Barbados: Public Health (Box 2)
    - Barbados: Health and Politics: A Public Lecture, 1991 (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Public health.
  - Barbados: Public Utilities (Box 2)
    - Report of the Public Utilities Board to the Governor-in-Executive Committee Under Section 52 of the Public Utilities Act of 1951 for the Year 1959, 1960; RISM 23086; Barbados. Public Utilities Board; 4 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Public utilities.
    - The Barbados Light & Power Company Limited; Half Year Report, 1992, RISM 23087; Barbados Light & Power Co.; 2.0 (Box 2)
      Public utilities.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Public Welfare (Box 2)
    - Annual Report of the Public Assistance Board, 1964-1965; RISM 20095; Barbados. Public Assistance Board; 18 pages (Box 2)
      Public welfare.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Religion (Box 2)
    - 150 Years of St. Judes, 1836-1986, ca. 1987; RISM 16952; 17 pages (Box 2)
      Religion; Barbados.
    - The Prophecy and the Law: Symbolism and Social Action in Seventh-Day Adventism, 1975; RISM 20060; Manning, Frank E.; p. 30-43. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Rum (Box 2)
    - "In the Lore of Barbados, Redistilled Rum", 1982; RISM 20079; Deitz, Paula; 1 page (Box 2)
      Rum.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Shipping (Box 2)
    - Annual Report of the Harbour & Shipping Master's Department for the Year 1957, 1958; RISM 23088; Barbados. Harbour & Shipping Master's Department; 17 pages (Box 2)
      Shipping.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Slavery (Box 2)
    - Lead Contact and Poisoning in Barbados Slaves: Historical, Chemical, and Biological Evidence, 1986; RISM 12329; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 399-425 (Box 2)
      Slavery.; Barbados.
    - Chronological Distribution of Enamel Hypoplasias and Weaning in a Caribbean Slave Population, 1985; RISM 12330; Corruccini, Robert S.; p. 699-711. (Box 2)
    - Weaning Among West Indian Slaves: Historical and Bioanthropological Evidence from Barbados, 1986; RISM 12331; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 111-117. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Slavery.
    - African Immigrants and their Descendants in Barbados: The Social and Cultural Life of a West Indies Slave Population, 1640-1834, 1969; RISM 12332; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 384-386. (Box 2)
    - Osteology of a Slave Burial Population from Barbados, West Indies, 1982; RISM 12333; Corruccini, Robert S.; p. 443-459. (Box 2)
    - Plantation Slave Life in Barbados: A Physical Anthropological Analysis, 1983; RISM 12334; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 65-90. (Box 2)
    - Carnelian Beads in Necklaces from a Slave Cemetery in Barbados, West Indies, 1979; RISM 12335; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 15-18. (Box 2)
    - Plantation Slavery on Barbados, West Indies, 1979; RISM 12336; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 45-52. (Box 2)
    - An Archaeological Investigation of the Domestic Life of Plantation Slaves in Barbados, 1972; RISM 12337; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 64-72. (Box 2)
    - Slave Revolts and Conspiracies in Seventeenth-Century Barbados, 1982; RISM 12381; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 5-42. (Box 2)
    - Escaping Bondage: The Odyssey of a Barbadian Slave Family, 1984; RISM 20096; Watson, Karl S., 1944-; 43 pages (Box 2)
    - An African Pipe from a Slave Cemetery in Barbados, West Indies, 1983; RISM 20097; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 245-253 (Box 2)
    - Slave Names and Naming in Barbados, 1650-1830, 1996; RISM 24360; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 685-726. (Box 2)
    - An African-Type Healer/Diviner and His Grave Goods: A Burial from a Plantation Slave Cemetary in Barbados, West Indies, 1997; RISM 24361; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 91-130. (Box 2)
    - Slave Medicine and Plant Use in Barbados, 1993; RISM 24362; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 74-98. (Box 2)
    - A Prone Burial from a Plantation Slave Cemetary in Barbados, West Indies: Possible Evidence for an African-type Witch or other Negatively Viewed Person, 1996; RISM 24364; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 76-86. (Box 2)
    - Determining African Birth from Skeletal Remains: A Note on Tooth Mutilation, 1994; RISM 24365; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 113-119. (Box 2)
    - Slave Medicine and Obeah in Barbados, circa 1650 to 1834, 2000; RISM 25620; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 57-90. (Box 2)
    - Congenital Syphilis in the Past: Slaves at Newton Plantation, Barbados, West Indies, 1992; RISM 25824; Jacobi, Keith P.; p. 145-158. (Box 2)
    - An African-Type Burial; Newton Plantation, Barbados, 1995; RISM 25835; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 4-6. (Box 2)
    - Problematical Glass Artifacts from Newton Plantation Slave Cemetery, Barbados, 1998; RISM 25836; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 5-7. (Box 2)
    - Inferring Fertility from Relative Mortality in Historically Controlled Cemetery Remains from Barbados, 1989; RISM 25837; Corruccini, Robert S.; p. 609-614. (Box 2)
    - Competing Discourses of Whiteness in the 1816 Barbados Enslaved Revolt: Theoretical Possibilities and Ethical Dilemmas, 2001; RISM 27402; Lambert, David; 10 pages; 10.0 (Box 2)
    - Plantation Slave Settlements in Barbados: 1650s to 1834, 2002; RISM 27506; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 121-161. (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Social Conditions (Box 2)
    - Social Inequality and Sexual Status in Barbados, 1977; RISM 16947; Sutton, Constance R.; p. 292-325. (Box 2)
    - The Differentiation of Economic Groups in the West Indies, 1961; RISM 16948; Cumper, George E. (George Edward), 1924-; 11 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Social Life and Customs (Box 2)
    - Dropping Remarks and the Barbadian Audience, 1976; RISM 24018; Fisher, Lawrence Edgar; p. 227-242. (Box 2)
      Manners and customs; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Soil (Box 2)
    - Barbados: An Act to Make Provision for the Improvement and Conservation of the Soil, 1958 (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Soils.
  - Barbados: Solar Stills (Box 2)
    - Description of the Construction of a 50 Sq. Ft. Wooden Roof-Type Solar Still in Barbados, 1962; RISM 20099; Lawand, Tom; 18 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Solar stills.
  - Barbados: Strikes and Lockouts (Box 2)
    - A Spontaneous Strike in Barbados: A Study of Structural Change and Conflict, 1966; RISM 24274; Sutton, Constance R.; 12 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Strikes and lockouts.
  - Barbados: Sugar Cane (Box 2)
    - Small-Scale Sugar Cane Farming in Barbados, 1966; RISM 12308; Handler, Jerome S.; p. 264-283. (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Sugarcane.
    - Sugar Cane Varieties in Barbados: An Historical Overview, 1958; RISM 20100; Stevenson, G. C.; 26 pages (Box 2)
    - The Yield of Sugar Cane in Barbados in 1963, RISM 20101; Inniss, B. de L.; 27 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Sugar Industry and Trade (Box 2)
    - The Sugar Industry of Barbados: A Method for Calculating the Price of Sugar-Cane, 1947; RISM 20102; Shephard, C. Y. (Cecil Yaxley); 41 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Sugar trade.
    - The Sugar Industry of Barbados, 1946 Crop; Report on the New Method of Remunerating Cane Cutters, RISM 20103; Shephard, C. Y. (Cecil Yaxley); 9 pages (Box 2)
    - A Report on the Present Condition and Future Outlook of the Sugar Industry of Barbados by the Delegates Appointed by the Legislature of Barbados, 1935; RISM 20104; 12 pages (Box 2)
      Sugar trade.; Barbados.
  - Barbados: Taxation (Box 2)
    - Barbados: Offshore Financial Center; The New U.S. Treaty, Low Tax Rates, and Other Attributes make Barbados an Attractive Site for Offshore Financial Operations - Particularly Captive Insurance Companies, 1986; RISM 20105; Brewer, Colin; p. 1-7 (Box 2)
      Taxation.; Barbados.
    - Explanation of Proposed Income Tax Treaty Between the United States and Barbados; Scheduled for a Hearing before the Committee on Foreign Relations, United States Senate, 1985; RISM 20106; United States. Congress. Joint Committee on Taxation; 51 pages (Box 2)
    - Tax Convention with Barbados: Message from the President of the United States, 1985; RISM 20107; United States. Congress. Senate; 25 pages (Box 2)
    - Agreement Between Canada and Barbados for the Avoidance of Double Taxation and the Prevention of Fiscal Evasion with Respect to Taxes on Income and On Capital, 1980; RISM 23342; 25 pages (Box 2)
    - "Built-In" Flexibility of Individual Income Taxation in an Underdeveloped Country: A Case Study, 1967; RISM 23946; Bonnett, Ronald L.; 17 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Tourism (Box 2)
    - The Influence of Tourism in Altering Values in Barbados, West Indies, undated; RISM 20108; Press, Clayton M.; 5 pages (Box 2)
      Tourism.; Barbados.
    - The Social Implications of Tourism, 1980; RISM 23953; Brathwaite, Farley; 15 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Trade Unions (Box 2)
    - Barbados Workers' Union: 14th Annual Report, 1955; RISM 23089; Barbados Workers' Union; 12 pages (Box 3)
      Barbados.; Labor unions
  - Barbados: Trade Unions: Sugar Workers (Box 2)
    - Rules and Regulations of the Barbados Sugar and General Workers Union, 1967; RISM 20109; Barbados Sugar and General Workers Union; 40 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Labor unions; Sugar workers.
  - Barbados: Transportation (Box 2)
    - Report and Minority Report of the Railway Commission, 1934; RISM 20110; Barbados. Railway Commission; 2 items (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Transportation.
  - Barbados: Windmills (Box 2)
    - Comments on the Brace Research Institute Windmill, 1969; RISM 22971; Wilson, A.; 2 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Windmills.
    - Brace Research Institute: Performance Test of a Savonius Rotor, 1964; RISM 22972; Simonds, M. H.; 17 pages (Box 2)
    - Performance Test of an 8 Meter Diameter Andreau Windmill, 1964; RISM 22973; Bodek, A.; 21 pages (Box 2)
  - Barbados: Women (Box 2)
    - Statement made in the House of Assembly on September 19, 1978 by the Honourable H. de B. Forde, Attorney General, RISM 20111; 3 pages (Box 2)
      Barbados.; Women.
  - Barbados: Youth (Box 2)
    - Case Study on "People of Tomorrow", 1989; RISM 20533; Bynoe, Joyce; 7 pages (Box 2)
      Youth.; Barbados.
- Belize (Box 3)
  - Belize (Box 2)
    - The Belize Newsletter, No. 25, July 1974; Belize. Government Information Service; 3 pages (Box 2)
      Belize.
  - Belize: Agriculture (Box 2)
    - Agriculture in British Honduras, undated; RISM 16703; Dumont, René; 14 pages (Box 2)
      Belize.; Agriculture.
    - Working Out or Working In: The Choice Between Wage Labor and Cash Cropping in Rural Belize, 1980; RISM 23968; Chibnik, Michael, 1946-; p. 86-105. (Box 2)
  - Belize: Antiquities (Box 2)
    - A Modified Interpretation of the "Giant Glyph" Altars at Caracol, British Honduras, 1954; RISM 16974; Satterthwaite, Linton, 1897-1978; 3 pages; p. 1-3. (Box 2)
      Belize.; Antiquities.
  - Belize: Bilingualism (Box 2)
    - The Cognitive Consequences of Bilingual Education in Northern Belize, ca. 1978; RISM 16934; Rubinstein, Robert A., 1951-; 43 pages (Box 2)
      Bilingualism.; Belize.
  - Belize: Black Carib Indians (Box 2)
    - The Evolution of a Playful Ritual: The Garifuna's John Canoe in Comparative Perspective, 1977; RISM 16986; Dirks, Robert V.; p. 89-109. (Box 2)
      Garifuna (Caribbean people).; Belize.
    - Revitalization Movements as Indicators of Complete Acculturation, 1974; RISM 16992; Sanford, Margaret S.; p. 504-518. (Box 2)
    - To Be Treated as a Child of the Home: Black Carib Child Lending in a British West Indian Society, 1975; RISM 16993; Sanford, Margaret S.; p. 159-181. (Box 2)
    - Alternative Therapeutic Systems in Belize: A Semiotic Framework, 1981; RISM 23165; Staiano-Ross, Kathryn, 1940-; p. 317-332. (Box 2)
      Belize.; Garifuna (Caribbean people).
    - Spirit Possession in Southern Belize, 1982; RISM 24024; Foster, Byron; p. 18-23. (Box 2)
    - Women, Households, and Transnational Migration Networks: The Garifuna and Global Economic Restructuring, 1996; RISM 25157; Matthei, Linda M.; p. 133-149. (Box 2)
  - Belize: Boundaries (Box 2)
    - International Boundary Study No. 161: Belize-Mexico Boundary, 1977; RISM 16978; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Intelligence and Research; 4 pages (Box 2)
      Belize.; Boundaries.
    - Developments in the Belize Question, 1946-1960, 1961; RISM 17152; Waddell, D. A. G (David Alan Gilmour), 1927-; p. 459-469. (Box 2)
    - More on the Belize Question, 1960; RISM 17151; Waddell, D. A. G (David Alan Gilmour), 1927-; 5 pages; p. 230-233. (Box 2)
  - Belize: Children (Box 3)
    - A Socialization in Ambiguity: Child-Lending in a British West Indian Society, 1974; RISM 17747; Sanford, Margaret S.; p. 393-400. (Box 3)
      Belize.; Children.
  - Belize: Descripton and Travel (Box 3)
    - Belize in Figures, 1989, RISM 16972; Belize. Government Information Service; 4 pages (Box 3)
    - Background Notes: Belize, 1980-2000; RISM 16973; United States. Department of State. Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs; 6 items; 9/80, 5/82, 8/87, 5/90, 11/94 and 4/00; no content (Box 3)
    - Fact Sheet: Belize, 1989; RISM 20112; Belize. Government Information Service; 9 pages (Box 3)
    - Notes on Conditions in Belize (British Honduras), 1971-1980; RISM 20113; Royal Commonwealth Society; 4 items; 10/71, 6/74, 4/78, 2/80; no content (Box 3)
    - Belize, Central America: A Pictoral History and a Full Color Map, 1987; RISM 23264; unpaged. (Box 3)
    - Belize City Map, 1982; RISM 15297; 2 pages (Box 3)
    - Belize, 2000; RISM 26329; 7 pages; 7.0 (Box 3)
  - Belize: Drug Trade (Box 3)
    - Maritime Counter-Drug Operations; Agreement Between the United States and Belize, 1992; RISM 17898; United States. Department of State; 7 pages (Box 3)
      Belize.; Drug traffic.
    - Narcotic Drugs: Illicit Production and Traffic; Agreement Between the United States and Belize and Amending Agreements, 1983; RISM 17899; United States. Department of State; 9 pages (Box 3)
    - Narcotic Drugs; Agreement Between the United States of America and Belize, 1989; RISM 23265; United States. Department of State; 5 pages (Box 3)
    - Narcotic Drugs: Illicit Production and Traffic; Agreement Between the United States of America and Belize Amending the Agreement, 1983-1984; RISM 23331; United States. Department of State; 2 pages (Box 3)
      Drug traffic.; Belize.
  - Belize: Economic Assistance (Box 3)